<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title></title>
  <subtitle>FoxGibbon is your source for design news &amp; tutorials. Whether professional or enthusiast, it is a place to find information, source inspiration &amp; seek help.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://foxgibbon.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href=""/>
  <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id></id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Smartsource</title>
    <link href="/projects/smartsource/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/smartsource/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;SmartSource was a solo project which followed the 4 D&#39;s design process. I conducted the research and defined all the contextual issues. I then conducted interviews, card sorting and bodystorming sessions with participants from SME&#39;s &lt;em&gt;(small, medium enterprises)&lt;/em&gt;. Participants were also asked to create photo diaries of their business waste material over a month. This produced a wealth of rich qualitative data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/smartsource/ss-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workshop visited for research&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/smartsource/ss-ae.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waste in skip&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Visiting small and medium enterprises to gain first hand
		qualitative data
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collected data was compiled and synthesised into key usability problems. This information was supported by creating customer journey maps, storyboards and mapping out user journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/smartsource/ss-uj.png&quot; alt=&quot;user journey map&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		User journey mapping
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/smartsource/ss-mm.png&quot; alt=&quot;mind map&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Stakeholder mapping
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/smartsource/ss-sb.png&quot; alt=&quot;story board&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Storyboarding user journeys
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone with experience in manufacturing industry and a passion for projects that help to support a green future, the main goal of the project, was to reduce the impact of manufacturing companies on national waste production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies involved in the process were incredibly happy with the final outcome and the prospects that the platform could offer them. Environmental, economic and social benefits were found to have been made clear through the branding and app onboarding, flow and features. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcza99.axshare.com&quot;&gt;View the live prototype here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/smartsource/ss-o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smartsource app screens&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Smartsource final outcome
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Recoll</title>
    <link href="/projects/recoll/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/recoll/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Education 4.0 is a purposeful approach to learning that lines up with the fourth industrial revolution and about transforming the future of education using advanced technology and automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design process followed the double diamond model. The primary focus of this project was providing value to users &lt;em&gt;(university students with high workloads)&lt;/em&gt; as well as making sure that the final output was feasible for developers. This required extensive multidisciplinary team working to ensure a productive and purposeful Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/recoll/rc-ai.png&quot; alt=&quot;AI structure&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Mapping out AI structure
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key insights from the initial research and discovery phases were achieved using literature reviews. Once we had developed some initial insights we tested them using storyboarding, observation and interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial wire-frames were sketched out on paper so team could get a mutual understanding of how the app would flow. The wire-frames were then transferred into Adobe Xd to create something more interactive and tangible.These designs were influenced by Android &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui&quot;&gt;User Interface, Navigation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/declaring-layout&quot;&gt;Layouts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure the prototype was suited to the defined users we sat down and observed them using the app, noting down key challenges and usability issues that were gathered using think aloud protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/recoll/rc-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;user testing&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Testing Xd wire-frames with users
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/recoll/rc-cj.png&quot; alt=&quot;customer journey mapping&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Mapping emotions throughout the app flow to identify strengths and weaknesses for development
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the project was to improve the university experience for those who were not feeling supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest challenge faced during the project was to provide this support without having a negative impact on the existing university services or increasing the workload of users &lt;em&gt;(students)&lt;/em&gt;. A secondary challenge was ensuring the Artificial Intelligence was relevant to the product and that data was handled ethically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were achieved with user testing and liaising with developers during the ideation, wire-framing and iteration stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent testing with the student body showed that participants felt the project was beneficial to the university experience and supported their education development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/recoll/rc-o.png&quot; alt=&quot;recoll app screens&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/recoll/rc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;recoll app mockup&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Final deliverables for the Recoll app
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ralph Lauren</title>
    <link href="/projects/ralph-lauren/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/ralph-lauren/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The design process followed the double diamond model. The first step was to conduct thematic, heuristic, satisfaction and performance related issues across the website. Issues were then catalogued to discover ways to make the site more intuitive and satisfying to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/ralph-lauren/rl-an.png&quot; alt=&quot;ralph lauren analysis&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Key findings from Heuristic, Performance and
		Satisfaction analysis
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the project, adding value to the Ralph Lauren website was particularly challenging. The company has a design team dedicated to improving sales and conversion rates. This meant that research and testing had to be highly user-focused to achieve a meaningful design outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/ralph-lauren/rl-t.png&quot; alt=&quot;user interviews&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Iterations were extensively tested to ensure
		statistically significant results
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing showed that there was a statistically significant decrease in SUS scores between the original website (w1) (M= 82.1.6, SD= 9.674) to the redesign (w2) (M= 89.1 SD= 10.126), t (25) = 3.013, p &amp;lt; .05 (two tailed). The mean difference in SUS scores was 7.0 The eta squared statistic (0.275) indicated a large effect size. A power of .90 was achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the Ralph Lauren redesign is more ‘usable’ and satisfying than the original website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are 90% certain this answer is correct and unaffected by chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/ralph-lauren/rl-e.png&quot; alt=&quot;ralph lauren wireframes&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/ralph-lauren/rl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ralph lauren mock-up on laptop&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Ralph Lauren wire-frame prototype and final deliverables
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Petlet</title>
    <link href="/projects/petlet/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/petlet/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The project followed the double diamond model. Emphasis was placed on the research and discovery phase, to emphasise the needs of the user. We made sure to use research processes that delivered real insights &lt;em&gt;(card sorting, interviews, observation)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/petlet/pl-e.png&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorming on whiteboards&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Mapping user journeys and key touchpoints to provide
		value to users
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this was a project with a quick turnaround. We ran a week long design sprint to iterate the app in collaboration with users. This was an excellent experience to work in a fast paced design environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/petlet/pl-j.png&quot; alt=&quot;design sprint process&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Stages of the week-long design sprint
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the project was to improve the lives of people who are caring for multiple pets. As pets are considered to be &amp;quot;part of the family&amp;quot;, one of the biggest challenges was conducting research respectfully. The data gathered related to personal lifestyle choices of the owners regarding their pets. Whilst being respectful and open, we also had to gather enough detail to produce a purposeful
design solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that all the information was thoroughly reviewed personas, experience maps and storyboards were used. This helped to ensure that the most meaningful insights, with the greatest value to users could be collated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/petlet/pl-em.png&quot; alt=&quot;experience map&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Experience mapping to gain further insight into the user
		process
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prototypes were extensively tested with defined target users. Users were encouraged to interact with the prototype app, this helped to ascertain if it was intuitive to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/petlet/pl-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;wireframes of petlet app&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Low fidelity wireframe sketches
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the project was to improve the lives of people who are caring for multiple pets. Our team achieved this by producing an app that linked key care components for each pet onto one system. Owners could easily access pet services such as veterinarians and petsitters, set tasks and routines for their pets; and while away, delegate those tasks to relevant carers remotely to monitor progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/petlet/pl-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;petlet app flow&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/petlet/pl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;petlet mobile mock up&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Deliverables for Tails.com from the research project
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mojeek</title>
    <link href="/projects/mojeek/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/mojeek/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the lead of Mojeek&#39;s website redesign, I spearheaded a comprehensive process that spanned over two years. With a focus on accessibility and user-centered design, the redesign journey aimed to enhance the website&#39;s usability and deliver an exceptional user experience. As a team, we embarked on a journey that involved various stages, including accessibility and heuristic reviews, user interviews, SUS testing, guided observation, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Research: Laying the Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To gain valuable insights into user needs and preferences, we conducted user interviews, engaging directly with representative users to understand their motivations, goals, and pain points. These interviews formed the foundation for informed design decisions and helped shape the redesign strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantitative measurements of usability were obtained through System Usability Scale (SUS) testing, coupled with guided observation to gather real-time feedback from users. This iterative process allowed for continuous refinement and enhancement of the website&#39;s design, informed by user insights and preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the two-year duration, findings from accessibility and heuristic reviews, user interviews, SUS testing, and guided observation were diligently collected and analyzed. Miro, an online collaboration platform, facilitated the organization and visualization of data, enabling me to prioritize and address identified issues and opportunities for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/mojeek/miro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;miro sorting template&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Example of one of the toolkits used to define future
		features of Mojeek.
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prototyping: Designing the User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prototypes and mock-ups were created iteratively, ensuring that design concepts were thoroughly explored and refined using Figma and Adobe XD. Concurrently, design system templates were developed to ensure consistency and efficiency throughout the design process, reinforcing a cohesive visual identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/mojeek/ip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;inner page redesigns in adobe xd&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Inner page redesigns in Adobe XD.
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing: Iterating for User Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website redesign process also incorporated a limited release to a community of users, allowing for iterative testing and continuous feedback. This approach ensured that the redesign met real-world usage requirements and evolving user expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, new features were introduced, including the implementation of personal search engines, which enabled users to customize their search experiences based on their preferences. These additions aimed to deliver a more personalized and tailored search journey, differentiating Mojeek from its competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/mojeek/cmm.png&quot; alt=&quot;mojeek community&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Mojeek community.
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of the comprehensive redesign efforts, Mojeek experienced significant growth in its user base, with the user count more than doubling over the two-year period. This expansion reflected the success of the redesign in attracting and engaging users, who responded positively to the improved accessibility, enhanced usability, and the personalized search experience. &lt;a href=&quot;www.mojeek.com&quot;&gt;See the live website here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/mojeek/am.png&quot; alt=&quot;mojeek about page&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Mojeek about page.
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/mojeek/mf.png&quot; alt=&quot;mojeek focus dashboard&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Mojeek focus: new feature that was implemented.
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Genshare</title>
    <link href="/projects/genshare/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/genshare/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The project followed the first half of double diamond model &lt;em&gt;(Discover and define)&lt;/em&gt;. Emphasis was placed on the research and discovery phase, to provide a service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;genshare&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaptioN&gt;
		GenShare - bringing generations together through shared
		experiences
	
&lt;/figcaptioN&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A range of different tools were used to frame the behaviours, pains, motivations and goals of users. This allowed us to identify the best opportunities to relieve these pains and add value to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-pm.png&quot; alt=&quot;marion persona&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-pc.png&quot; alt=&quot;charlie persona&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Defining behaviours, pains, motivations and goals of
		users
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-sb.png&quot; alt=&quot;storyboard&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Storyboarding to understand how users will become aware
		and interact with the service
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-vm.png&quot; alt=&quot;value proposition marion&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-vc.png&quot; alt=&quot;value proposition charlie&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Using value proposition canvas to identify the best
		opportunities to relieve pains and add value to users
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-mc.png&quot; alt=&quot;social business model canvas&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		The social business model canvas was used to define key
		activities, relationships, segments and channels that
		would be required to get the business running
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-cm.png&quot; alt=&quot;customer journey map&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Customer journey mapping was used to develop the stages
		users will follow from discovering the service, through
		to leaving it
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-bp.png&quot; alt=&quot;service
	blueprint&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		A service blueprint was used to develop the channels and
		support processes needed by the service
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-sm.png&quot; alt=&quot;stakeholder map&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Stakeholder mapping was used to define who would
		facilitate and who would be impacted by the service
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the project was to improve the lives of elderly people following the Covid-19 pandemic. One of the biggest challenges was conducting research with no direct access to user. The data gathered related to primary data collection &lt;em&gt;(books, personal sources, journals, newspapers, websitess, government records).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/genshare/sd-oc.png&quot; alt=&quot;genshare outcome&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Final service concept and value proposition
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>FoxGibbon</title>
    <link href="/projects/foxgibbon/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/foxgibbon/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the dynamic world of UX and UI design, staying updated with the latest trends, techniques, and best practices is crucial. Recognizing this need, I embarked on a creative journey and established FoxGibbon.com, a blog dedicated to sharing valuable UX and UI design tips and information. This article will delve into the process of creating the blog, which involved extensive research, prototyping, testing, leveraging analytics, and employing AI to enhance articles and receive valuable suggestions. Furthermore, I will outline how I crafted the logo and branding to establish a strong visual identity for FoxGIbbon.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Research: Laying the Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in creating FoxGibbon.com was to conduct research. This involved studying the latest industry trends, analyzing popular design blogs, and understanding the target audience&#39;s needs and preferences. By identifying knowledge gaps and areas where I could add value, I set the direction for my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Logo and Branding: Establishing Visual Identity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/foxgibbon/ideation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;foxGibbon website&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;text-slate-500 m-2&quot;&gt;
		Early sketches of FoxGibbon logo
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/foxgibbon/logo-bw.png&quot; alt=&quot;foxGibbon website&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		FoxGibbon logo and branding process
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the significance of visual identity in brand establishment, I undertook the task of designing a unique logo and branding. Through careful consideration of typography, color schemes, and graphic elements, I crafted a visually appealing logo that captured the essence of the blog&#39;s focus on UX and UI design. The branding was extended across various touchpoints, including the website, social media profiles, and promotional materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prototyping: Designing the User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a clear vision in mind, I began prototyping the blog&#39;s user experience. I focused on creating an intuitive and visually appealing interface, ensuring easy navigation and seamless accessibility of content. Employing wireframing and rapid prototyping techniques, I iteratively refined the design to optimize user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Analytics and AI Integration: Enhancing Content and Engagement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continuously improve the quality of articles and engage readers effectively, I integrated the use analytics and AI technologies. By analyzing user behavior, such as page views, time spent on articles, and click-through rates, I gained valuable insights into popular topics and reader preferences. Additionally, leveraging AI tools like ChatGPT, I enhanced articles by incorporating relevant suggestions
and providing personalized recommendations to readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hotjar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating FoxGibbon.com was a rewarding journey, driven by a passion for UX and UI design. Through extensive research, prototyping, and testing, I crafted a user-centric blog that provides valuable insights to its readers. By integrating analytics and AI technologies, I continually enhance the quality of content and engage readers effectively. The logo and branding contribute to a strong visual identity, reinforcing the blog&#39;s credibility and attracting a loyal community of design enthusiasts. As FoxGIbbon.com continues to grow and evolve, it remains dedicated to sharing the latest UX and UI design trends and helping designers create exceptional user experiences. &lt;a href=&quot;www.foxgibon.com&quot;&gt;See the live website here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/foxgibbon/web.png&quot; alt=&quot;FoxGibbon web&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		FoxGibbon web
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CDM</title>
    <link href="/projects/cdm/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/cdm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Initial discussions were made with clients to define what they were looking for in a logo. After this the brand, website and values were analysed to generate logo ideas that were relevant and provided the correct tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cdm-is.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;initial sketches&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Initial sketches to define logo ideas
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cdm-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;workshop visited for research&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cdm-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;workshop visited for research&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cdm-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;workshop visited for research&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cdm-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;workshop visited for research&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Initial iterations of logos made in Adobe Illustrator
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies involved in the process were incredibly happy with the final outcome. only one iteration was required. &lt;a href=&quot;https://competitivedigitalmarkets.eu/&quot;&gt;View the Competitive Digital Markets site here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cdm-oc.png&quot; alt=&quot;cdm final logo&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/cdm/cd-cp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cdm final logo&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Coalition for Competitive Digital Markets final outcome
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Armourslice</title>
    <link href="/projects/armourslice/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/armourslice/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The design process followed the double diamond model, the biggest focus for this project was improving the usability and efficiency of the current armourslice cable stripping tool. I also needed to ensure the final product was feasible for mass manufacture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Initial concept sketches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a range of concepts using a refined success criteria. The tool was required to fit into confined work spaces while remaining ergonomically sound. Through questionnaires, interviews and prototype testing I refined the idea to maximise usabilty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/armourslice/as.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sketches for ripple project&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Keyshot renders of final deliverable
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was to improve the function and efficiency of the C.K tools&#39; current line of armourslice SWA cable strippers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research, specification and final concept were taken for development and manufacture by the C.K product development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/armourslice/as-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ripple product mockup&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/armourslice/as-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ripple 3d model&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		Keyshot renders of final deliverable
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Algopigm</title>
    <link href="/projects/algopigm/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/projects/algopigm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The project was very developer focused. It involved me learning how the blockchain has become programmable with smart contracts, little pieces of automatically-executing code running on the blockchain. It also involved creating a hosted website where people could learn about the project and purchase the NFT&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/algopigm/ap-e.png&quot; alt=&quot;algopigm code&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;A look at the image compiler created in Node &lt;/em&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the project was to learn more about cryptocurrency, the blockchain, NFT&#39;s and improve my skills as developer. As this was one of my biggest solo projects, one of the major challenges was being able to develop a solution that had the necessary functionality for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure the outcome was successful, the website and designs were tested with prospective customers over several iterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/algopigm/ap-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;algopigm art&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;Algopigm character designs&lt;/em&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome was a fully responsive website and a random algorithmically generated composite PNG image maker built in Node JS. The final NFT&#39;s are available both on the website and on OpenSea.io&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algopigm.com&quot;&gt;live project&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ThomasMott/algopigm&quot;&gt; repository&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensea.io/collection/algopigm&quot;&gt; OpenSea collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/projects/algopigm/ap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;algopigm on phone and laptop&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;Final deliverable - Algopigm website&lt;/em&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
